[
    {
      "question": "What is MySQL?",
      "option": [
        "A relational database management system",
        "Developed, distributed, and supported by Oracle Corporation",
        "All the options are correct",
        "Cross-platform, open-source and free"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MySQL statement is used to select data from a database?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT",
        "GET",
        "EXTRACT",
        "OPEN"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MySQL statement is used to update data in a database?",
      "option": [
        "UPDATE",
        "INSERT",
        "MODIFY",
        "SAVE"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MySQL statement is used to delete data from a database?",
      "option": [
        "DELETE",
        "REMOVE",
        "COLLAPSE"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MYSQL statement is used to insert new data in a database?",
      "option": [
        "INSERT NEW",
        "ADD RECORD",
        "INSERT INTO",
        "ADD NEW"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how do you select a column named \"FirstName\" from a table named \"Persons\"?",
      "option": [
        "EXTRACT FirstName FROM Persons",
        "SELECT Persons.FirstName",
        "SELECT FirstName FROM Persons"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how do you select all the columns from a table named \"Persons\"?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT *.Persons",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons",
        "SELECT [all] FROM Persons",
        "SELECT Persons"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how do you select all the records from a table named \"Persons\" where the value of the column \"FirstName\" is \"Peter\"?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName<>'Peter'",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter'",
        "SELECT [all] FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE 'Peter'",
        "SELECT [all] FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter'"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how do you select all the records from a table named \"Persons\" where the value of the column \"FirstName\" starts with an \"a\"?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE '%a'",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='%a%'",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='a'",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE 'a%'"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "The OR operator displays a record if ANY conditions listed are true. The AND operator displays a record if ALL of the conditions listed are true",
      "option": [
        "False",
        "True"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how do you select all the records from a table named \"Persons\" where the \"FirstName\" is \"Peter\" and the \"LastName\" is \"Jackson\"?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter' AND LastName='Jackson'",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName<>'Peter' AND LastName<>'Jackson'",
        "SELECT FirstName='Peter', LastName='Jackson' FROM Persons"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how do you select all the records from a table named \"Persons\" where the \"LastName\" is alphabetically between (and including) \"Hansen\" and \"Pettersen\"?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT LastName>'Hansen' AND LastName<'Pettersen' FROM Persons",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE LastName BETWEEN 'Hansen' AND 'Pettersen'",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE LastName>'Hansen' AND LastName<'Pettersen'"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MySQL statement is used to return only different values?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT DIFFERENT",
        "SELECT DISTINCT",
        "SELECT UNIQUE"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MySQL keyword is used to sort the result-set?",
      "option": [
        "SORT",
        "SORT BY",
        "ORDER BY",
        "ORDER"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how can you return all the records from a table named \"Persons\" sorted descending by \"FirstName\"?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT * FROM Persons SORT BY 'FirstName' DESC",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons SORT 'FirstName' DESC",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER FirstName DESC",
        "SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER BY FirstName DESC"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how can you insert a new record into the \"Persons\" table?",
      "option": [
        "INSERT INTO Persons VALUES ('Jimmy', 'Jackson')",
        "INSERT VALUES ('Jimmy', 'Jackson') INTO Persons",
        "INSERT ('Jimmy', 'Jackson') INTO Persons"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how can you insert \"Olsen\" as the \"LastName\" in the \"Persons\" table?",
      "option": [
        "INSERT INTO Persons (LastName) VALUES ('Olsen')",
        "INSERT INTO Persons ('Olsen') INTO LastName",
        "INSERT ('Olsen') INTO Persons (LastName)"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you change \"Hansen\" into \"Nilsen\" in the \"LastName\" column in the Persons table?",
      "option": [
        "UPDATE Persons SET LastName='Nilsen' WHERE LastName='Hansen'",
        "MODIFY Persons SET LastName='Hansen' INTO LastName='Nilsen",
        "UPDATE Persons SET LastName='Hansen' INTO LastName='Nilsen'",
        "MODIFY Persons SET LastName='Nilsen' WHERE LastName='Hansen'"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how can you delete the records where the \"FirstName\" is \"Peter\" in the Persons Table?",
      "option": [
        "DELETE ROW FirstName='Peter' FROM Persons",
        "DELETE FROM Persons WHERE FirstName = 'Peter'",
        "DELETE FirstName='Peter' FROM Persons"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "With MySQL, how can you return the number of records in the \"Persons\" table?",
      "option": [
        "SELECT LEN(*) FROM Persons",
        "SELECT NO(*) FROM Persons",
        "SELECT COUNT(*) FROM Persons",
        "SELECT COLUMNS(*) FROM Persons"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the supported types of joins in MySQL?",
      "option": [
        "INNER JOIN, LEFT JOIN, RIGHT JOIN, CROSS JOIN",
        "INNER JOIN, OUTER JOIN, LEFT JOIN, RIGHT JOIN"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which operator is used to select values within a given range?",
      "option": [
        "UNION",
        "BETWEEN",
        "IN",
        "RANGE"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "The NOT NULL constraint enforces a column to not accept NULL values.",
      "option": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which operator is used to search for a specified pattern in a column?",
      "option": [
        "GET",
        "LIKE",
        "FROM"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which MySQL statement is used to create a database table called 'Customers'?",
      "option": [
        "CREATE TABLE Customers",
        "CREATE DATABASE TABLE Customers",
        "CREATE DB Customers",
        "CREATE DATABASE TAB Customers"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    }
  ]